Commission on General Education Records 1986-1990
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Commission on General Education Records
1986-1990
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 217
1 linear feet 1 containers
Consist chiefly of minutes, reports, and research material.
Organizational History:
The Commission on General Education was formed in 1986. Some activities were supported by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities. Its purpose was to review and, if needed, recommend changes in the general education requirements at Washington State University. Its final report came out in February, 1989, with extensive revisions recommended. These recommendations were the basis for revising WSU's general education requirements, beginning in 1990. The commission was chaired by University Executive Vice-President and Provost, Albert C. Yates, and Vice-Chair was Robert A. Littlewood, Anthropology. Other members included Richard Law, Division of Humanities and Social Sciences; Donald Bushaw, Vice Provost for Education; John Kicza, History; James Quann, Registrar; and Birgitta Ingemanson, Foreign Languages and Literatures.
Records of the Commission on General Education consist chiefly of minutes, reports, and research material. The records were received in folders, which are retained with the same headings. Materials within folders are arranged chronologically, with undated material placed at the end of the year in which it was found. Some material was clipped together; in these cases the undated materials within these groups are kept together. Other groups are broken up and arranged chronologically with the rest. Other materials, such as articles, advising materials, etc., are left in original order.
The Collection is open for research use.
Records of the Commission on General Education, Washington State University, were transferred to the University Libraries in 1992 (UA92-42) by Professor Robert Littlewood, retired from the Dept. of Anthropology.
Littlewood, Robert, 1930---Archives
Washington State University. Commission on General Education--Archives; Washington State University. Commission on General Education--Records and correspondence; Washington State University--Curricula--Research--Archives
General education--Washington (State)--History
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Commission on General Education Meetings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Commission on General Education Meetings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Commission on General Ed. Meetings, Jan-Apr 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Commission on General Ed. Meetings, May-Dec 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Commission on General Education Meetings, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Education Materials, 1985-May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Education Materials, June-Oct 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General Education Materials, Nov-Dec 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Education Materials, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Education Materials, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- General Education Materials, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General Education Materials, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gen. Ed. Materials-"Good Practices in General Education" (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Gen. Ed. Commission-Tier I Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Gen. Ed. Commission-Tier II Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder Is)
- Gen. Ed. Commission-Tier III Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 16)
- World Civilizations course material (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Interim report for NEH-Year 1, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- WSU Report on the Humanities Core Curriculum Project, Sep.1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- General Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- General Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Commission on General Ed.-Final Report, Feb 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Off-Campus/Branch Campus Material (Box 1, Folder 23)
- State of WA-Higher Ed. Coordinating Board Materials (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Student/Faculty Development-Advising Materials (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Articles concerning general education (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Articles concerning general education (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Material on the philosophy of a university (Box 1, Folder 28)